# TEO, BRENDAN WEI ZHI

## Front-End Web Developer

• : + 6016 - 383 6202 : brendan\_twz@hotmail.com : linkedin.com/in/brendantwz : github.com/Brendantwz

#### **About Me**

4-years of professional experience as an Engineer. Biggest highlight of my career is being able to work with multi-talented experts on a common goal and optimizing 44% churn out rate with scripting tools. Nevertheless, I am self-driven equipped with growth-mindset. Currently, I am spearheading into Full-stack Web development. Seeking a career change to a position involving Web Development.

#### **Work Experience**

### Freelance – Penang, Malaysia

Front-end Web Developer

( Nov 2023 - Current )

• Acquired a client from a Mixed-martial arts gym in Penang called Wasp MMA Gym to deliver a single infographic page that gives an overview of services that the gym offers. Goal is to outreach and channel cold-leads to warm-leads.

#### Intel Corporation – Penang, Malaysia

SoC Design Engineer

(Apr 2022 – Jun 2023)

- Developed and implemented scripts to improve debugger's day-to-day debugging task using AutoHotkeys tool, optimized users' effectiveness to churn out failing log by 44%. Documentation was put in place for repeatability usages.
- Analyzed and root-caused failing tickets filed by debuggers, 59 unique failing tickets are converged and reproduced with documentation in the span of 3-months of working on new Meteor lake e-core and server related project.
- Discovered 19 design and simulator bugs. It was raised and coordinated with technical lead and principal engineer to have a work-around while working with respective experts. The bugs are validated with fixes and closed within the average span of 3-weeks.
- Collaborated 2 cross team (Pre-silicon Validation and Lab Team) to maintained project delivery timeline. By supporting on post-silicon debugging challenges with respective stakeholder.

Soft-IP Validation Engineer

(Mar 2021 - Apr 2022)

- Managed and execute 6 features based on test plans. Closely working with Micro-arch Designer and Test-plan owner on the expectancy behavior of the plan on Alderlake and Meteorlake Gen5 PCle IP project.
- Developed and deploy email reporting system towards my team of 5 using CRON tool. Improve work efficiency by 15% from needing to manually extract test results.
- Developed and implemented a bucketization (bucket failures based on signature) script which will sort out 5+ unique failing buckets from 10000+ test seeds based on the weekly regression ran.

Graduate Technical Trainee

(Nov 2019 - Mar 2021)

- Supported a feature owner by shadowing as an execution owner to validate RTL designs and test writing.
- Delivered 1st level bug/error with data log to revise with feature owner. Solved 27 high-level errors independently.
- Managed 1 sub-feature while improving regression passing rate 60% to 87% and coverage points rate 30% to 72% on Alderlake project within 1-month
- Collaborated cross team support (Link Layer Team) on supporting regression script maintenance. Reduced weekly test regression execution breakdown from 3 to 1 a month (Dropped by 66%)

#### **Personal Project**

SimplyPress – a simple blog post project that is branded as a plan, draft and customize your next release of article blog. Created using EJS, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js and Bootstrap

#### Education

#### Northumbria University Newcastle

Bachelor in Electrical and Electronic Engineering (1st CLASS HONOURS)

Graduation Date: Oct 2019

Graduation Date: Nov 2017

Organizations/Awards: Silver Medalist Innovative Project, Student Advisor for Engineering Society and Organizing Team

#### **KDU Penang University College**

Diploma in Electrical and Electronic Engineering (Microelectronics) (CGPA: 3.74)

Organizations/Awards: Dean's Honor List, Peer-Assisted Study Session tutor, 1st Runner Up IHL-Malaysia Start-up Challenge

# Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, Bootstrap, Git, Python Script, Perl Script, Batch Script, UNIX Shell Script, Debugging, Command Prompt, Linux Env, Test Planning & Validation, Microsoft Office Suite

## **Soft Skills**

Communication, Analytical, Detail-oriented, Interpersonal, Time Management, Adaptable, Creative Problem-Solving, Teamwork, Self-Awareness, Creativity

#### Certifications

Career Essentials in Generative AI by Microsoft & LinkedIn, Ethics and Legal Compliances, Information Security and Privacy Awareness, Privacy Essentials Handling Personal Data, GitHub Dos and Don'ts, Secret Management in Software Development, MYTRIZ Creative Problem-Solving Level 1 Practitioner

Language **English** (Native Speaker), **Mandarin** (Proficient), **Malay** (Elementary)

Co-Founder of Wasp MMA Gym – Ms Claire Li Ji **References** E: wasp.mmagym@gmail.com M: +60-12-728-7232

SoC Design Engineer - Mr Shien Jee, Kang E: shien.jee.kang@intel.com M:+60-11-6461-7399